stuart dykes BSC: DEA: GDA

24 Ormonde Drive • Maghull • Merseyside • L31 7AP **TEL** 07734 739 045 • **E-MAIL** studykes@yahoo.com

PROFILE

I am a hardworking and ambitious individual with knowledge and experience from many years involvement within the construction industry. Bringing a close attention to detail, I offer a positive attitude with strong communication skills and an excellent knowledge of IT and Microsoft packages. Always reliable, I believe I provide excellent site and team management skills and as well as being a strong team player, I feel I am equally adept to work alone and use my own initiative. In the workplace I am dependable and I endeavour to perform any task accurately. I am always eager to learn new skills and further develop and enhance my existing skills, knowledge and experience.

EXPERIENCE

Building Supervisor – Sovini LIVERPOOL, NORTH WEST, UK – JUNE 2016 - PRESENT

- Working within the Development department of Sovini, I assist the project managers with controlling and overseeing numerous new build development contracts around Merseyside, Lancashire and Cheshire. These range from traditional build developments to timber frame schemes with the construction of houses, apartments and walk-up flats being the main area of development. I'm involved in the development a variety of products with a mixture of specifications including residential outright sale units, 'shared-ownership', rent-to-buy and social rent.
- A large proportion of my role is to provide a 'Clerk of Works' service where I visit site and review our new build schemes on a daily basis, building up relationships with contractors and sub-contractors and assisting in creating a product that is built to the highest standard. My duties include reviewing progress on these schemes, assisting the site manager in appraising works, checking the build matches working drawings and confirming the product provided is the product we pay for. I am continually monitoring onsite works but throughout the final stages of construction, my role allows me to survey these properties and (where necessary) produce defect reports for the plot and issue to site so as to ensure the unit is handed over 'defect' free.
- An additional part of my role is to liaise with our Sales team and with their customers and 'iron out' any customer care issues. This usually involves a visit to the property and liaise with the resident to survey the issue before progressing with any proposed resolution.

Projects Surveyor & Manager - Westdale Services Ltd LIVERPOOL, NORTH WEST, UK - FEB 2009 - JAN 2016 (REDUNDANCY)

- Managing the North West division of Westdale Service Ltd, I work within the field of external insulation & render systems for both private and social clients performing full external building refurbishments.
- Duties include all elements of surveying & management of construction works. Duties consist of full site
 measures for both proposed and existing works, carrying out building & property surveys, perform
 Domestic Energy Assessments, undertaking pre and post work inspections and maintenance surveys,
 estimating and building up costs for bills of quantities to tender for works, compiling monthly
 valuations, perform stock takes and produce stock forecasting models for use with site works, manage
 and organise all material orders for projects, manage accounts and wages for sub-contractors,
 managing sub-contractors and supervising their works, programming works, ensuring weekly progress
 summaries & forecasts are produced on time and to schedule, price for any and all variations, support

the Site Manager to deliver works on time, assist with the running of site programmes and ensure works run to the agreed time scales, assist with general health and safety compliance & office management.

Graduate Manager - Persimmon Homes North West

NORTH WEST, UK – JULY 2007 – FEB 2009 (REDUNDANCY)

- Employed on Graduate Management Programme
- Duties included working through all company departments including Land, Technical, Sales, Accounts, Commercial & Construction to understand the business as a whole.
- Main activities included to assist the Site Manager on a 13 acre new build scheme for 6 months before further time spent within the Customer Care department organising & scheduling maintenance & remedial works on properties and dealing with surveying issues forwarded from clients and NHBC.

Manager & Owner - DB Developments, Liverpool

NORTH WEST, UK, - OCT 2005 - JUNE 2007

- Managing my own business carrying out minor construction and refurbishment works within the residential sector.
- Skills include organising and managing both time, materials and subcontractors, liaising with clients and general building construction and maintenance.

Assistant Builder - WEB Joinery Ltd, Liverpool

NORTH WEST, UK, - 2001 - OCT 2005 (PREVIOUSLY EMPLOYED PART TIME THROUGHOUT 1995 - 1997)

• Main activities included all elements of building construction & joinery, basic labouring and training. Proficient and trained in using various tools, equipment and materials.

Leak Detection Technician - Environmental Detection Surveys (EDS), Southport

NORTH WEST, UK, - AUG 1997 - MAR 2000

As a team leader/supervisor my main activities included managing team members, organising surveys &
work deployment, learning and using computer and correlator techniques, performing valve and water
work operations, working to deadlines, map reading, driving, liaising with customers.

EDUCATION

(2018) CITB: Site Management Safety Training Scheme (SMSTS) - May 18 (Expires: May 2023)

(2018) Asbestos Awareness

(2017) Scaffold Awareness

(2014) CITB Managers & Professionals Health, Safety & Environment Test - CSCS: AQP Card (White)

(2014) City & Guilds, Level 3: Green Deal Advisor

(2013) City & Guilds, Level 3: Domestic Energy Assessor

(2011) St John Ambulance - First Aider at Work 3 day

(2011) EURO 1: Fork Lift Truck Training (Counterbalance)

(2001 – 2004) Liverpool John Moores University, Liverpool

- HND Building Surveying
- Graduated BSc (Hons) Construction Management (2:2)

(1995 – 1997) Deyes High School, Liverpool

• A-Levels (A-E) in Media Studies, English Language, General Studies.

(1990 - 1995) Deyes High School, Liverpool

• GCSE's (A-C) in English Literature, English Language, Math's, History, Duel Science, I.T., Design Technology, Religious Studies, Art.

REFERENCES

On request.